Bukhosi Ngqabutho Khumalo

Nationality: Zimbabwean (+7) 9223493155 (+263) 773865233 **Date of birth:** 22/09/1993

▼ Twitter: https://twitter.com/BK_KaMangethe

► YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCcrefamjJGW3qizlIx3tdqQ

• Address: Genk House 5, 2nd Floor, , 614068 Perm (Russia)

• Address: Nhlanhla Secondary School PO BOX 36 Mtabisa, Lupane (Zimbabwe)

ABOUT ME

Cartographer and GIS Analyst specializing in land and water resources management, territorial planning, disaster risk reduction and management and climate change adaptation. With a strong background in Spatial database management, satellite image analysis, map design, web map development and automation. Well versed in GIS softwares such as ArcGIS, MapInfo, QGIS, Geoserver, PostGIS and Agisoft Metashape and also programming languages such as python, JAVA (frontend), CSS, HTML and MySQL.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Geographic information systems officer

Dabane Water Workshops [31/07/2016 - 30/07/2017]

Address: 13 Cathkin Lane Avenue Burnside, Bulawayo (Zimbabwe) - http://dabane.org

City: Bulawayo **Country:** Zimbabwe

Email address: info@dabane.org

Name of unit or department: Non Governmental Organisation - Business or sector: Other service activities

- I worked under the Integrated Water Resource Management Programme and also on other programmes like Amalima, Women Empowerment and Access to Resources, Sustainable Energy for rural communities.
- Mapping project activities and satellite image analysis
- Hydrogeological surveys, social and physical dam feasibility surveys.
- Environmental Management plans for Sand River Water Harvesting systems.
- Soil and runoff modelling.
- Sand river water harvesting systems designs.
- Rangeland and infield soil and water conservation works.
- Rain water Harvesting systems.
- Holistic Land Management .
- Climate smart Agriculture
- Activity, monthly, quarterly and annual report writing.
- Baseline surveys, mid term reviews and End of project evaluation.

Contract teacher

Public Service Commission [31/12/2013 - 30/07/2014]

City: Lupane

Country: Zimbabwe

- Business or sector: Education

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Masters Degree in Cartography and Geoinformatics

Perm State university [01/08/2020 - 19/07/2022]

Address: 15 Bukireva Street Perm, 614990 Perm (Russia)

http://en.psu.ru

Field(s) of study: Mathematical and Cartographic modelling of geo Systems and complexies.

Final grade: First class (5)

Thesis: Modeling of Water Erosion in the Umzingwane River Watershed for Integrated Water Resources

Management in Zimbabwe

- Geoinformation mapping of nature, population, economy and ecological situations.
- Geoinformation technologies for the organization of monitoring and forecasting of emergency situations.
- Remote sensing practice
- Territorial planning
- Automation using python
- Internet mapping technologies
- Operational mapping technologies

Bachelor of social science degree in Geography and Population Studies

Lupane state university [31/07/2014 – 30/07/2018]

Address: Head office PO BOX 170B, Lupane (Zimbabwe)

http://www.lsu.ac.zw

Field(s) of study: Social sciences

Final grade: First class - Level in EQF: EQF level 6

National classification: Zimbabwe National Qualification Framework level 8

Thesis: A time series modelling of soil loss using the RUSLE model in Shake Catchment, Gwanda, Zimbabwe

Courses covered include Geographic Information Systems, Remotesensing, Soil science, climate and meteorology, Environmental Impact Assessment, Disaster Risk reduction and management, water resources management, hydrology, sustainable natural resources management, population programmes and policies, HIV and AIDS, Epidemiology, Research methods and techniques in geography, Waste management and Data analysis and computing.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Ndebele | Shona

Other language(s):

English Russian

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C2 LISTENING B1 READING B1 WRITING B1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C2 SPOKEN INTERACTION C2 SPOKEN PRODUCTION B1 SPOKEN INTERACTION B1

DIGITAL SKILLS

My Digital Skills

Tableau / Geoserver / MapInfo / adobe photoshop Adobe Ilustrator Adobe Indesign Adobe Dreamweaver / Agisoft Metashape / QGIS - Quantum GIS / Google Earth Engine / Geo ODK / Python / crop wat / HEC-HMS / Microsoft Office (Word Excel) / SPSS software (Statistical Package for Social Science) / SAS Planet / ArcGIS pro/ ArcGIS online/ Collector / ERDAS Imagine / Web Programming: HTML, CSS, Javascript (front-end), Java (back-end)

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: B1
Driving Licence: BE
Driving Licence: BE

CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS

Sinovuyo positive teen parenting for healthy families workshop

[Maphisa, Matobo District, 30/09/2019 - 04/10/2019]

The training was conducted by Insiza Godlwayo Aids Council and other partners. I was trained on how to facilitate workshops on Positive parenting. I gained critical skills like the steps involved in building a happy family, problem solving, budgeting, saving, disciplining and communication in the familly. I also gained facilitation skills

MANAGEMENT AND LEADERSHIP SKILLS

Leadership and innovation

- Former Deputy Headboy of Luveve High School
- Founder of the Lupane State University Environmental Club and the Lupane State GeoSpatial Society
- Founder of Catch them Young Academy Lupane and also the current board strategic planner
- Founder of the Sobendle Football Association which I utilized to reduce alchohol abuse, crime rate and other social ills among young people in rural areas of Lupane.

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Personal Traits

- Can work effectively with others in a team.
- Excellent communication skills
- Excellent essay and report writting skills
- Ability to utilize graphics design and video editing softwares.
- Can work under pressure and meet deadlines
- Multi-lingual.

HONOURS AND AWARDS

Better Schools Programme Award for having atleast 13 points at Alevel (Reigate District)

Better Schools Programe Zimbabwe [06/03/2014]

2 University Book prices and Vice Chancellors book price

Lupane state University [25/10/2018]

Award for the best graduating student in Geography and Population studies

Lupane state university [25/10/2018]

Board of honor in the department of Cartography and Geoinformatics for achievements in educational activities

Perm State University [2021]

I was enlisted in the board of honor of the department of Cartography and Geoinformatics after achieving a distinct average score of 5.0.

RECOMMENDATIONS

Academic Supervisor

Name: Olga Bezerina

Email: berezina_olga@psu.ru

Academic supervisor at Perm State University, Russia

Lecturer and Department Chairperson

Name: Mr Nkululeko Ndiweni Phone number: (+263) 7727300463 Email: njndiweni@gmail.com

He is the chairperson at the department of Geography and Geoinformation sciences at Lupane State University. He taught me courses such as climate change adaptation and mitigation and research methods in human

geography

Lecturer and project supervisor

Name: Mr Phibion Chiwara

Phone number: (+263) 773682822 Email: <u>Pchiwara8@hotmail.com</u>

Chiwara was my lecturer at Lupane State University. He taught courses such as Remote sensing and Geographic Information systems. He also supervised me on my dissertation and was also my academic supervisor during internship

Lecturer

Name: Ilya Bryzhko

Phone number: (+7) 9028372117 Email: <u>zemproekt@yandex.ru</u>

Lecturer at Perm State University, Russia